Guide to the Hermann Broch Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1907-86; Series I; 7.5; (20 boxes)
  - CORRESPONDENCE OF HERMANN BROCH
    - Bourgoing, Jean, Baron de, 1950 Mar 17 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Bourgoing, Mila, 1946 Dec 9 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Brandeis University Library
      See: William Leibowitz, Box 8 folder 224
    - Broch, Franziska von Rothermann ("Fanny"), 1907-09 (Box 1, Folder 35-40)
    - Broch, Franziska von Rothermann ("Fanny"), 1907-51 (Box 2, Folder 41-53)
    - Broch, Friedrich Josef ("Fritz"), 1927-51, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Broch, Josef and Johanna, 1924-36 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Broch de Rothermann, Hermann Friedrich, 1921-48 (Box 3, Folder 56-72)
    - Broch de Rothermann, Hermann Friedrich, 1949-51 (Box 4, Folder 73-77)
    - Bródy, Dániel and Daisy
      See: Rhein-Verlag, Box 10 folder 303
    - Brunngraber, Rudolf, 1947-51 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Buck, George C., 1950-51 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Bunzel, Joseph and Gertrude, 1937-51, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 80-84)
    - Burger, Karl, 1946 Apr 4 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Burgmüller, Herbert, 1934-50 (Box 4, Folder 86-87)
      Includes transcripts
    - Butler, Charles Edward, 1949-51 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1939-49, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Canby, Marion Ponsonby Gause ("Lady"), 1939-51 (Box 5, Folder 90-102)
    - Canetti, Elias, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Cantril, Hadley, 1942-48 (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Chisholm, Hugh
    - Chronos Verlag
      See: Martin Mörike, Box 9 folder 252
    - Church Peace Union
      See: Carl Hermann Voss, Box 15 folder 419
    - Claassen Verlag, 1947-51 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Cohen, Elliot Ettelson, 1948 Dec 9 (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Colby, Frances
      See: Frances Colby Rogers, Box 11 folder 329
    - Colliers Magazine
      See: Henry La Cossitt, Box 8 folder 215
    - Commentary, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - Condell, Margherita, 1949-51 (Box 6, Folder 108)
    - Corbett, Percy S., 1945 Oct 27 (Box 6, Folder 109)
    - Csokor, Franz Theodor, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - Deutsche Akademie für Sprache und Dichtung, 1950-51 (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - Diamond, David, 1946-49 (Box 6, Folder 112)
    - Ditzen, Rudolf (a.k.a. Hans Fallada), 1934 Nov 27 (Box 6, Folder 113)
    - Dukas, Helene, 1945-70 (Box 6, Folder 114)
    - Dumann, Erich, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 115)
    - Ebel, Walter, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 116)
    - Einstein, Albert, 1939, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 117)
    - Eisner, Pavel, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - Emrich, Wilhelm, 1950-51 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - Epstein, Monique, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - Europa Verlag
      See: Emil Oprecht, Box 9 folder 271
    - Faber du Faur, Curt von, 1945-50 (Box 6, Folder 121)
    - Fallada, Hans
      See: Rudolf Ditzen, Box 6 folder 113
    - Federn, Paul, 1944-48 (Box 6, Folder 122)
    - Feigl, Dr., 1951 May 8 (Box 6, Folder 123)
    - Feldmann, Theo, 1931-51 (Box 6, Folder 124)
    - Feuchtwanger, Lion, 1947 Mar 22 (Box 6, Folder 125)
    - [Ficker ?], 1914, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 126)
    - Fischer Verlag (S. Fischer Verlag), 1930-34, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 127-31)
    - Fischer-Hölzl, Marta (photocopies only), 1945-50 (Box 6, Folder 132)
    - Flores, Angel, 1934 Jul 16 (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - Franck, James, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - Frank, Waldo, 1946-51, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - Freeman, Joseph, 1943-47 (Box 6, Folder 136)
    - Frei, Bruno, 1948 Jun 3 (Box 6, Folder 137)
    - Friedländer, Adolf Albrecht and Emmy, 1938-49 (Box 6, Folder 138)
    - Friedmann, Anette, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 139)
    - Friedrich Schiller Universität
      See: Anna Lindemann, Box 8 folder 229
    - Fritz-Vietta, Egon and Dory, 1947-51 (Box 6, Folder 140-42)
    - Fülöp-Miller, Erika, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 143)
    - Fülöp-Miller, Réné, 1944-50 (Box 6, Folder 144)
    - Fülsdorf, Volkmar, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 145)
      See: Volkmar von Züllsdorf, Box 16 folder 452
    - Gaede, Professor, 1943 Feb 21 (Box 6, Folder 146)
    - Gallimard, Gaston
      See: Raymond Queneau, Box 10 folder 296
    - Gauss, Christian Frederick, 1942-50 (Box 6, Folder 147)
    - Gebser, Jean, 1948 Oct 14 (Box 6, Folder 148)
    - Geiringer, Gertrude ("Trude"), 1938-51 (Box 6, Folder 149-50)
    - Giese, Nora, 1950 May 11 (Box 6, Folder 151)
    - Glaubach, Susi, 1945 Oct 31 (Box 6, Folder 152)
    - Glick, Nathan, 1950 Feb 10 (Box 6, Folder 153)
    - Goldstein, Kurt, 1951 Feb 7 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Goll, Yvan (includes photocopies), 1939-48 (Box 7, Folder 155)
    - Greenberg, Clement
      See: Commentary, Box 5 folder 107
    - Grössinger, Josephine, 1946 Aug 2 (Box 7, Folder 156)
    - Grossmann, Walter, 1951 Feb 16 (Box 7, Folder 157)
    - Günther, Otto, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 158)
    - Gütersloh, Albert Paris, 1946 Oct 27 (Box 7, Folder 159)
    - Guérin, Daniel, 1951 May 7 (Box 7, Folder 160)
    - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation (John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation), 1942-51 (Box 7, Folder 161)
    - Gurian, Waldemar, 1946-47 (Box 7, Folder 162)
    - Hakel, Hermann, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - Hamburger Akademische Rundschau
      See: Hans-Joachim Lang, Box 8 folder 217, Karl Ludwig Schneider, Box 12 folder 352
    - Heimann, Dr., 1950 Dec 9 (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - [Heller ?], 1945 Jul 10 (Box 7, Folder 165)
    - Heller, Judith B., 1950 Dec 29 (Box 7, Folder 166)
    - Heller, Victor, 1943 Dec 2 (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - Henry Regnery Co., 1950 Oct 12 (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - Hertz, Richard, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 169)
    - Hertz, Robert, 1949 Jul (Box 7, Folder 170)
    - Herzfelde, Wieland, 1944-46 (Box 7, Folder 171)
    - Herzog, Anja, ca. 1950 (Box 7, Folder 172)
    - Hewett-Thayer, Harvey W., 1944 Nov 23 (Box 7, Folder 173)
    - Hirsch, Rudolf, 1949-51 (Box 7, Folder 174)
    - Hönigwald, Richard, 1943 Dec 12 (Box 7, Folder 175)
    - Hofmann, Else, 1945, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 176)
    - Horch, Franz, 1933-45 (Box 7, Folder 177)
    - Horkheimer, Dr., 1945 Oct 2 (Box 7, Folder 178)
    - Horst, Karl August, 1951 Apr 11 (Box 7, Folder 179)
    - Hovde, Bryn J.
      See: New School for Social Research, Box 9 folder 262
    - Hudson, Stephen
      See: Sydney Schiff, Box 12 folder 349
    - Huebsch, Benjamin W., 1934-40 (Box 7, Folder 180)
    - Hutchinsons International Authors
      See: Robert Neumann, Box 9 folder 261
    - Huxley, Aldous, 1943-45, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 181)
    - Ingalls, Jeremy, 1951 Jun 3 (Box 7, Folder 182)
    - Italiaander, Rolf, 1948 Jan 2 (Box 7, Folder 183)
      See also: Frank and Yvonne Thiess, Box 13 folder 379
    - Jacobi, Jolande Székács (photocopies), 1936-44 (Box 7, Folder 184)
    - Johnson, Alvin Saunders, 1949-51 (Box 7, Folder 185)
      See also: New School for Social Research, Box 9 folder 262
    - Jolas, Eugene, 1948-49 (Box 7, Folder 186)
    - Judd, Jadwiga, ca. 1941 (Box 7, Folder 187)
    - Kahler, Alice Loewy ("Lili"), 1943-51 (Box 7, Folder 188)
    - Kahler, Antoinette ("Mama"), 1941-51 (Box 7, Folder 189)
    - Kahler, Erich, 1940-51 (Box 7, Folder 190-93)
    - Kahler, Francis, 1947-48 (Box 8, Folder 194)
    - Kahler, Josephine ("Fine"), 1943-51 (Box 8, Folder 195)
    - Kahler, Victor and Bettina, 1945-48 (Box 8, Folder 196)
    - Kahn, Robert A., 1947 Apr 6 (Box 8, Folder 197)
    - Kaprinay-Krancsic, Karoly von, 1951 Jan 25 (Box 8, Folder 198)
    - Kasack, Hermann, 1949 Mar 6 (Box 8, Folder 199)
    - Kerényi, Karl, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 200)
    - Kessler, B., 1948 Jul 14 (Box 8, Folder 201)
    - Kesten, Hermann, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 202)
    - Kindler, Hermann, 1947 Jun 24 (Box 8, Folder 203)
    - Klarmann, Adolf D. (Adolf Donald), 1948 Dec 7 (Box 8, Folder 204)
    - Klimpt, Werner, 1948-50 (Box 8, Folder 205)
    - Knopf, Inc. (Alfred A. Knopf, Inc.), 1948-51 (Box 8, Folder 206)
    - Kohn, Albert, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 207)
    - Kohn, Hans, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 208)
    - Kolb, Annette, 1944-45 (Box 8, Folder 209)
    - Kongress für kulturelle Freiheit
      See: Edouard Roditi, Box 11 folder 328
    - Kraft, Werner, 1948-50 (Box 8, Folder 210)
    - Krafft-Kennedy, Ludwig, 1935 Oct 24 (Box 8, Folder 211)
    - Krechevsky, Isadore, 1939 Aug 19 (Box 8, Folder 212)
    - Krell, Max, 1930-51 (Box 8, Folder 213)
      See also: Ullstein Verlag, Box 13 folder 382
    - Kristeller, Paul Oskar, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 214)
    - La Cossitt, Henry, 1945 Jan 19 (Box 8, Folder 215)
    - Landauer, Georg, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 216)
    - Lang, Hans-Joachim, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 217)
    - Langgässer, Elisabeth, 1948-49 (Box 8, Folder 218)
    - Lapan, Arthur, 1948-49 (Box 8, Folder 219)
    - Lasky, Melvin J., 1949-50 (Box 8, Folder 220)
    - Lauterbach, Leo, 1949-51 (Box 8, Folder 221)
    - Lederer-Eckardt, Gertrud, 1948 Jan 7 (Box 8, Folder 222)
    - Lehner, Fritz, 1949-50 (Box 8, Folder 223)
    - Leibowitz, William, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 224)
    - Lens, Miriam Beer-Hofmann, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 225)
    - Levy, Beryl Harold, 1950, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 226)
    - Levy, Edith Jonas, 1947-51 (Box 8, Folder 227-28)
    - Lindemann, Anna, 1948-49 (Box 8, Folder 229)
    - Die literarische Welt
      See: Arthur Rosen, Box 12 folder 334
    - Loewenfeld, Philipp, 1943-48 (Box 8, Folder 230)
    - Loewy, Hanna, 1945 Jun (Box 8, Folder 231)
    - Lowe, Adolph, 1945-48 (Box 8, Folder 232)
    - Lowe, Helen Tracy Porter, 1951 Jan 3 (Box 8, Folder 233)
    - Ludovyk-Gyömröi, Edith
      - Correspondence, 1918-51 (Box 8, Folder 234-36)
      - Excerpts from correspondence by Hermann Broch de Rothermann, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 237)
      - Commentary on correspondence by Hermann Broch de Rothermann, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 238)
      - Supplementary materials, 1918-72 (Box 8, Folder 239)
    - Ludwig, Emil, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 240)
    - Maier, Nani, 1948-50 (Box 9, Folder 241)
    - Manheim, Dr., 1939 Jul 17 (Box 9, Folder 242)
    - Mann, Thomas (printed version and photocopies), 1944-51 (Box 9, Folder 243-44)
      See also: Hans Reisiger, Box 10 folder 299
    - Marck, Professor, 1940 Mar 8 (Box 9, Folder 245)
    - Maril, [Konrad ?], 1934 Nov 25 (Box 9, Folder 246)
    - Marshall, John
      See: Rockefeller Foundation, Box 11 folder 327
    - Mazenod, Lucien
    - Meeske, Harold, 1950 Sep 2 (Box 9, Folder 247)
    - Meisel, James Hans, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 248)
    - Mellon, Paul, 1948 Feb 14 (Box 9, Folder 249)
    - Merz, Ferdinand, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 250)
    - Meyer, Georg Heinrich
    - Meyer-Abich, Adolf, 1951 Apr 25 (Box 9, Folder 251)
    - Mörike, Martin, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 252)
    - Der Monat
      See: Melvin J. Lasky, Box 8 folder 220
    - Morris, Wright, 1949 Dec 15 (Box 9, Folder 253)
    - Morwitz, Ernst, 1945 Sep 9 (Box 9, Folder 254)
    - Muir, Edwin and Willa, 1931-33 (Box 9, Folder 255)
    - Mumford, Lewis, 1946 Jan 9 (Box 9, Folder 256)
    - Musil, Robert, 1933-40 (Box 9, Folder 257)
    - Neider, Charles, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 258)
    - Neilson, William Allan and Elisabeth, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 259)
    - Nettl, Margaret von Gutfeld, 1948 Sep 10 (Box 9, Folder 260)
    - Die neue Rundschau
      See: Rudolf Hirsch and, Box 7 folder 174, Dolf Sternberger, Box 12 folder 374
    - Neumann, Robert, 1944-50 (Box 9, Folder 261)
    - New School for Social Research, 1946-50 (Box 9, Folder 262-63)
      See also: Adolf Lowe, Box 8 folder 232, Alvin Saunders Johnson, Box 7 folder 185, Bryn J. Hovde, Box 7 folder 179, Hans Staudinger, Box 12 folder 368
    - Norden, Heinz, 1948 Jul 26 (Box 9, Folder 264)
    - Norden, Hermine, 1949 Nov 3 (Box 9, Folder 265)
    - Nordwestdeutscher Rundfunk, 1949-50 (Box 9, Folder 266)
    - O'Conner, William Van, 1948 Aug 9 (Box 9, Folder 267)
    - Oeser, Oscar, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 268)
    - Österreichisches Tagebuch
      See: Bruno Frei, Box 6 folder 137
    - Oppenheim, Paul, 1945-50 (Box 9, Folder 269)
    - Oppenheim-Errera, Gabrielle, 1945 Aug 6 (Box 9, Folder 270)
    - Oprecht, Emil, 1947-51 (Box 9, Folder 271)
    - Oxam, Garfield Bromley, 1946-47 (Box 9, Folder 272)
    - Pantheon Books
      See also: Kurt and Helen Wolff, Box 15 folder 442
      - Correspondence, 1937-51 (Box 9, Folder 273-75)
      - Royalty statements, 1947-51 (Box 9, Folder 276)
    - Paschal, Marian, 1944 Oct 27 (Box 9, Folder 277)
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1948 Jun 2 (Box 9, Folder 278)
    - Pechel, Rudolf
      See: Deutsche Akademie für Sprache und Dichtung, Box 6 folder 111
    - P. E. N. Club, 1949-50 (Box 9, Folder 279)
      See also: Franz Theodor Csokor, Box 6 folder 110
    - Pfeffer, Max, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 280)
    - Pfeiffer, Ernst, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 281)
    - Pick, Robert, 1951, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 282)
    - Plank, Robert, 1939-47 (Box 9, Folder 283)
    - Plunguian, Gina, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 284)
    - Pönninger, Anna, 1951 Jan 27 (Box 9, Folder 285)
    - Polak, Ernst and Delphine (photocopies only), 1939-50, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 286)
    - Polgar, Alfred, 1945-49 (Box 10, Folder 287)
    - Pollak, Max, 1944-45 (Box 10, Folder 288)
    - Polzer, Anne, 1948 Oct 8 (Box 10, Folder 289)
    - Polzer, Victor, 1936-51 (Box 10, Folder 290)
    - Possony, Stefan, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 291)
    - Prescott, Joseph, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 292)
    - Princeton University Library, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 293)
    - Princeton University Press, 1945-46 (Box 10, Folder 294)
    - Pulver-Feldmann, Berta, 1942-45 (Box 10, Folder 295)
    - Queneau, Raymond, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 296)
    - Raven-Kindler, Nina, 1948 May 24 (Box 10, Folder 297)
    - Regler, Gustav, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 298)
    - Reisiger, Hans, 1946-49 (Box 10, Folder 299)
    - Reiss, Erich, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 300)
    - Reiwald, Paul, 1946-51 (Box 10, Folder 301-02)
    - Rhein-Verlag, 1930-33 (Box 10, Folder 303-12)
    - Rhein-Verlag, 1934-51 (Box 11, Folder 313-24)
    - Richter, Werner, 1943-51 (Box 11, Folder 325)
    - Ripper, Rudolph C. von, 1945-50 (Box 11, Folder 326)
    - Rochowanski, Leopold Wolfgang
      See: Agathonverlag, Box 1 folder 2
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1941-50, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 327)
    - Roditi, Edouard, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 328)
    - Rogers, Frances Colby, 1942-50, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 329-30)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1946 Jun 22 (Box 12, Folder 331)
    - Roosevelt College, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 332)
    - Rosé, Alfred E., 1947 Sep 3 (Box 12, Folder 333)
    - Rosen, Arthur, 1947 Jun 21 (Box 12, Folder 334)
    - Rosenfeld, Paul, 1945-46 (Box 12, Folder 335)
    - Rosenthal, Annina, 1942 May 18 (Box 12, Folder 336)
    - Roth, William, 1947-51 (Box 12, Folder 337)
    - Rothstein, Irma, 1946-51, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 338-39)
    - Rous, Mr., 1949 Feb 10 (Box 12, Folder 340)
    - Rütten & Loening, 1950 Jan 5 (Box 12, Folder 341)
    - Sachs, Hanns, 1943-45 (Box 12, Folder 342)
    - Sahl, Hans, 1943-50 (Box 12, Folder 343-44)
    - Saiko, George, 1947-51 (Box 12, Folder 345)
    - Salinger, Herman, 1948-50 (Box 12, Folder 346)
    - Sapper, Theodor, 1950-51 (Box 12, Folder 347)
    - Sauerländer, Wolfgang
      See: Pantheon Books, Box 9 folder 272
    - Schabert, Kyrill
    - Schiff, Doris, 1948 Jun 8 (Box 12, Folder 348)
    - Schiff, Sydney and Violet (a.k.a. Stephen Hudson), 1943-49 (Box 12, Folder 349)
    - Schiffer, Helene ("Max"), 1949-50 (Box 12, Folder 350)
    - Schiffrin, Jacques
    - Schnabel, Erwin ("Harry"), 1949-50 (Box 12, Folder 351)
    - Schneider, Karl Ludwig, 1948-49 (Box 12, Folder 352)
    - Schönwiese, Ernst, 1946-51 (Box 12, Folder 353)
    - Schrecker, Paul, 1944-47 (Box 12, Folder 354)
      See also: Alfred Stern, Box 12 folder 372
    - Schweiger, Hertha, 1945 Jan 30 (Box 12, Folder 355)
    - Schweizer, Siegfried, 1949 May 22 (Box 12, Folder 356)
    - Schweizers Rest Farm, 1949 May 15 (Box 12, Folder 357)
    - Schwerin, Dr., 1951 May 16 (Box 12, Folder 358)
    - Sebba, J., 1951 Apr 26 (Box 12, Folder 359)
    - Seelig, Carl, 1946-50 (Box 12, Folder 360)
    - Segall, Berta, 1949-50 (Box 12, Folder 361)
    - Sherwood, Robert E., 1945 May 25 (Box 12, Folder 362)
    - Short, William F., 1948 Nov 29 (Box 12, Folder 363)
    - Slade, Caroline, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 364)
    - Smith, Datus Clifford
      See: Princeton University Press, Box 10 folder 294
    - Sonne, Abraham, 1944-50 (Box 12, Folder 365)
      See also: Georg Landauer, Box 8 folder 216, Leo Lauterbach, Box 8 folder 221
    - Spender, Stephen (Box 12, Folder 366)
    - Spitz, René Arpad, 1943 Jul 28 (Box 12, Folder 367)
    - Staudinger, Else, 1937-50, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 368)
    - Staudinger, Hans
    - Steiner, Herbert, 1947-52, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 369)
    - Steinfeld, Friedrich, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 370)
    - Steinitz, Mr., 1947 Feb 21 (Box 12, Folder 371)
    - Stern, Alfred, 1946 Jul 23 (Box 12, Folder 372)
    - Stern, James, 1948-51 (Box 12, Folder 373)
    - Sternberger, Dolf, 1949-50 (Box 12, Folder 374)
    - Stout, Rex, 1945 May 10 (Box 12, Folder 375)
    - Strauss, Leo, 1948 May 15 (Box 12, Folder 376)
    - Suhrkamp, Peter, 1938 Mar 7 (Box 12, Folder 377)
    - Suhrkamp Verlag
      See: Dolf Sternberger, Box 12 folder 374
    - Taucher, Franz, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 378)
    - Thiess, Frank and Yvonne, 1930-51 (Box 13, Folder 379)
    - Torberg, Friedrich, 1943-51 (Box 13, Folder 380)
    - Uhse, Bodo, 1949-51 (Box 13, Folder 381)
    - Ullstein Verlag, 1933 (Box 13, Folder 382)
    - United States Army
      See: Karl Burger and Nathan Glick, Box 6 folder 153 and Box 4 folder 85
    - United States Post Office, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 383)
    - Untermeyer, Jean Starr
      - Broch to Untermeyer, 1939-44 (Box 13, Folder 384-95)
      - Broch to Untermeyer, 1945-51, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 396-409)
      - Untermeyer to Broch, 1941-49, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 410-14)
    - Viertel, Berthold, 1943-49, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 415)
    - Vietta, Egon
      See: Egon Fritz-Vietta, Box 6 folder 140
    - Voegelin, Erich, 1944-48 (Box 15, Folder 416)
    - [Vogt, Carl ?], 1945 Aug 8 (Box 15, Folder 417)
    - Vogue (Box 15, Folder 418)
    - Voss, Carl Hermann, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 419)
    - Waldinger, Ernst, 1945-51 (Box 15, Folder 420)
    - Die Wandlung
    - Wassermann, Julia, 1951 Mar 6 (Box 15, Folder 421)
    - Weidlé, Wladimir, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 422)
    - Weigand, Felicia (Box 15, Folder 423)
    - Weigand, Hermann John, 1945-49 (Box 15, Folder 424)
    - Weismann, Willi
      See: Willi Weismann Verlag, Box 15 folder 431
    - Weiss, Berthold M., 1948 Nov 17 (Box 15, Folder 425)
    - Weyl, Hermann, 1949-50, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 426)
    - Wheelwright, Philip Ellis, 1948-51 (Box 15, Folder 427)
    - Whyte, James, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 428)
    - Wilder, Isabel, 1944 Oct 18 (Box 15, Folder 429)
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1940-43 (Box 15, Folder 430)
    - Willi Weismann Verlag, 1947-51 (Box 15, Folder 431-36)
    - Winter, Hanns von, 1950-51 (Box 15, Folder 437)
    - Wittels, Fritz, 1942 Aug 3 (Box 15, Folder 438)
    - Wittenberg, Philip, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 439)
    - Wittlin, Joseph, 1945-49 (Box 15, Folder 440)
    - Wolf, Felix, 1926 (Box 15, Folder 441)
    - Wolff, Kurt and Helen, 1945-49 (Box 15, Folder 442)
      See also: Pantheon Books, Box 9 folder 272
    - Wyatt, Fritz and Gerty, 1944-51, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 443)
    - Yaddo, 1949 Mar 30 (Box 15, Folder 444)
    - Yale University, 1949-51 (Box 15, Folder 445)
      See also: James Tinkham Babb, Box 1 folder 13
    - [Young ?], Douglas [also identified as Norman Douglas], 1939 Dec 14 (Box 15, Folder 446)
    - Young, Stanley, 1944 Feb 3 (Box 15, Folder 447)
      See also: Bollingen Foundation, Inc., Box 1 folder 26
    - Zand, Herbert, 1948-51 (Box 16, Folder 448)
    - Zimmer, Christiane, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 449)
    - Zoff, Otto, 1948 Feb 16 (Box 16, Folder 450)
    - Zsolnay Verlag
      See: Franz Horch, Box 7 folder 177
    - Zuckerkandl, Mimi, 1945 Aug 21 (Box 16, Folder 451)
    - Züllsdorf, Volkmar von (part photocopies), 1939-50 (Box 16, Folder 452-55)
    - Zweig, Stefan (photocopies only), 1930-40 (Box 16, Folder 456-57)
    - Zylberberg, Hélène, 1950 Jan 16 (Box 16, Folder 458)
    - Unidentified, 1941-45 (Box 16, Folder 459)
  - CORRESPONDENCE OF KAHLER FAMILY
    This subseries represents third-party correspondence usually between Erich and Alice Lowey Kahler and friends and colleagues of Hermann Broch concerning the author.
    - Alvaro, Corrado, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 460)
    - Arendt, Hannah, 1951-56 (Box 17, Folder 461)
    - Barczay, Mrs. I., 1984 Sep 27 (Box 17, Folder 462)
    - Berryman, John, 1951 May 4 (Box 17, Folder 463)
    - Bertelsmann Verlag (C. Bertelsmann Verlag), 1957 (Box 17, Folder 464)
    - Black, Robert, 1986 Jul 15 (Box 17, Folder 465)
    - Blum, Ernst, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 466)
    - Bollingen Foundation, Inc.
      See: Vaun Gillmor, Box 17 folder 492
    - Borgese, Elisabeth Mann, 1951 Jun 7 (Box 17, Folder 467)
    - Broch, Annemarie Meier-Graefe, 1945-66 (Box 17, Folder 468-69)
    - Broch de Rothermann, Hermann Friedrich ("Armand"), 1986 Dec 19 (Box 17, Folder 470)
    - Bródy, Dániel, 1951-58 (Box 17, Folder 471-74)
    - Brude-Firnau, Gisela R., 1964-79 (Box 17, Folder 475)
    - Bunzel, Joseph H., 1951-68 (Box 17, Folder 476)
    - Canby, Henry Seidel and Marion Ponsonby Gause, 1951-61 (Box 17, Folder 477)
    - Dejon, Hedwig S., 1952 (Box 17, Folder 478)
    - Dukas, Helen, 1971 Feb 4 (Box 17, Folder 479)
    - Einstein, Albert, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 480)
    - Erfla, Marthe, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 481)
    - Faber du Faur, Curt von, 1952-58, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 482)
    - [Falkenburg ?], 1951 Jun 30 (Box 17, Folder 483)
    - Federn, Ernst, 1955 (Box 17, Folder 484)
    - Feldman, Theo, 1951 (Box 17, Folder 485)
    - Ferand, Emmy, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 486)
    - Fischer Verlag (S. Fischer Verlag), 1951 (Box 17, Folder 487)
    - Flinker, Martin, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 488)
    - Fried, John H. E. (with eulogy on Hannah Arendt), 1976 Aug 28 (Box 17, Folder 489)
    - Gauss, Christian Frederick, 1942-45 (Box 17, Folder 490)
    - Geiringer, Gertrude ("Trude"), 1952-63 (Box 17, Folder 491)
    - Gillmor, Vaun, 1951, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 492)
    - Glick, Nathan, 1951 Jun 13 (Box 17, Folder 493)
    - Goetz-Wittels, Poldi R., 1951 May 31 (Box 17, Folder 494)
    - Hassold, Ernest C., 1952-53 (Box 17, Folder 495)
    - Haydn, Hiram, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 496)
    - Herzog, Anja, 1955-69, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 497)
    - Jaffé, Aniela, 1954-72 (Box 17, Folder 498)
    - Johnson, Alvin Saunders, 1951-75 (Box 17, Folder 499)
    - Jonas, Klaus W., 1954-70 (Box 17, Folder 500)
    - Kahler, Alice Loewy ("Lili") and Erich (to one another), 1947-52 (Box 17, Folder 501)
    - Kahler, Edith, 1951 Jun 25 (Box 17, Folder 502)
    - Kahler, Victor, 1951 May 31 (Box 17, Folder 503)
    - Kiener, Julius, 1963-64 (Box 17, Folder 504)
    - Koebner, Thomas, 1964 Oct (Box 17, Folder 505)
    - Krafft-Kennedy, Ludwig, 1952 May 20 (Box 17, Folder 506)
    - Lange, Victor, 1951 May 31 (Box 17, Folder 507)
    - Lens, Miriam Beer-Hofmann, 1948-83 (Box 17, Folder 508)
    - Lerner, Max, 1965 Nov (Box 17, Folder 509)
    - Levy, Edith Jonas, 1951, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 510)
    - Lipman-Wulf, Peter, 1969 Dec 20 (Box 17, Folder 511)
    - Loewenthal, Minnie L., 1951-62, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 512)
    - Lowe, Helene Tracy Porter, 1951 May 31 (Box 17, Folder 513)
    - Lützeler, Paul Michael, 1973 Jul (Box 17, Folder 514)
    - Mann, Thomas, 1943-54 (Box 17, Folder 515)
    - Meisel, Marianne, 1951 (Box 17, Folder 516)
    - Moras, Joachim, 1954 Jan (Box 17, Folder 517)
    - Norden, Hermine, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 518)
    - Pick, Robert, 1951-55 (Box 17, Folder 519)
    - Plunguian, Gina, 1950 Mar 24 (Box 17, Folder 520)
    - Politzer, Heinz, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 521)
    - Polzer, Victor, 1951-65 (Box 17, Folder 522)
    - Princeton University Library, 1986 May 20 (Box 17, Folder 523)
    - Reiss, Erich, 1949 Jun 1 (Box 17, Folder 524)
    - Rosé, Alfred E., 1952 Feb 20 (Box 17, Folder 525)